<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on phasewalk1</title><link>https://phasewalk1.github.io/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on phasewalk1</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://phasewalk1.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://phasewalk1.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phasewalk1.github.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="tldr">TLDR&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>21 y.o. Fullstack Engineer from the East Bay, California. Passionate about all things computation: &lt;em>Cryptography&lt;/em>, &lt;em>AI&lt;/em>, &lt;em>Scientific Computing&lt;/em>, and more. I&amp;rsquo;m a privacy advocate, and a transhumanist techno-optimist.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Hi, my name is &lt;strong>phasewalk1&lt;/strong> and I study &lt;strong>Mathematical Computation Theory&lt;/strong> &amp;ndash; at the time of writing this I&amp;rsquo;m finishing up Differential Equations at Diablo Valley College, and will soon be transferring to either UC Santa Cruz or UC Davis, where I plan on participating in undergraduate research. I began my schooling studying applied mathematics, then shortly after shifted to computer science. I took my undergraguate CS courses in C++ and learned Python in my free time. By the time I completed Data Structures/Algorithms and Assembly Programming I was beginning to seek connections online with other programmers. It was then that I went down the rabbit hole of Twitter, 4chan, lainchan, and other online communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These communities opened a new world to me. One that shifted my perspective on programming from being a purely pragmatic pursuit to a more philosophical one. Writings such as Erich Hughes&amp;rsquo; &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.activism.net/cypherpunk/manifesto.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Cypherpunk Manifesto&lt;/a>, and Aaron Swartz&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a class="link" href="https://archive.org/details/GuerillaOpenAccessManifesto/mode/2up?view=theater" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Guerilla Open Access&lt;/a> greatly influenced me to think deeper about the implications of my studies.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>What is the most important thing you could be working on in the world right now? &amp;hellip; And if you&amp;rsquo;re not working on that, why aren&amp;rsquo;t you?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- Aaron Swartz&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It was people like Swartz and Hughes that made me realize that I wanted to be a part of something bigger than myself. I wanted to contribute to the world in a meaningful way. I wanted to make an impact. I wanted to be a part of the solution. I wanted to be a part of the revolution &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I shifted my focus away from slinging code for money and instead began to study the theory of computation. I wanted to understand the fundamentals, and how they can be applied to solve real world problems. My biggest passions lay in Cryptography, Privacy, and Security. I&amp;rsquo;m also interested in Machine Learning, Abstract Algebra, and Transhumanist Philosophy, but I&amp;rsquo;ll save those for another time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My heart beats for the future, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see what it holds.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>A better world is possible, let&amp;rsquo;s build it&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Archives</title><link>https://phasewalk1.github.io/archives/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phasewalk1.github.io/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Resource</title><link>https://phasewalk1.github.io/resource/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phasewalk1.github.io/resource/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://phasewalk1.github.io/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phasewalk1.github.io/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>